<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<databaseChangeLog
	xmlns="http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog/1.7"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog/1.7
         http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog/dbchangelog-1.7.xsd">

	<changeSet id="0018-roles-data" author="Eugene A. Kalosha">

		<sql>

			ALTER TABLE roles ALTER COLUMN description SET DATA TYPE character varying (512);

INSERT INTO roles (id, name, description) VALUES
(170, 'CEO', 'Chief Executive Officer (CEO) responsible to increase the value of the company.'),
(171, 'CRO', 'Chief Risk Officer (CRO) is responsible for the enterprise risk of the company including cyber risk management.'),
(172, 'CISO', 'Chief Information Security Officer (CISO). A CISO is a senior-level executive within an organization responsible for establishing and maintaining the enterprise vision, strategy, and cyber security program to ensure digital assets are adequately protected.'),
(173, 'CLM', 'Compliance Manager. A compliance manager or officer is an employee whose responsibilities include ensuring the company complies with its outside regulatory requirements and internal policies.'),
(174, 'DPO', 'The DPO must ensure that the organization complies with GDPR regulation if it processes EU citizen privacy data regardless of where it is located.  The DPO must have a deep knowledge of the GDPR and an awareness where possible regulatory breaches may occur.'),
(175, 'REM', 'Remediator. Fixes vulnerabitlities, incidents and cyber security findings.'),
(176, 'SYSOWN', 'System Owner. Is repsonsible for all decisions regarding the use and maintenance of the system.'),
(177, 'INFOSEC', 'InfoSec Focal Person. Is the point person that works with a system or process from the information security team.'),
(178, 'TSM', 'Task Manager. Owns a specific task or activity in the organization.'),
(179, 'PM', 'Project Manager. Manages a specific project in an organization.'),
(180, 'BUO', 'BU Owner. Is responsible for all decisions regarding the use and maintenance of the business unit.'),
(181, 'AUD', 'Auditor. IT Auditors are responsible for developing, planning, and executing IT audit programs based on risk assessments in a highly integrated audit environment.'),
(182, 'RISKMAN', 'Risk Manager. Responsible to create the risk model. Manages risk of a specific nature.'),
(183, 'PRCOWN', 'Process Owner. Is responsible for all decisions regarding the use and maintenance of the process.');

			ALTER SEQUENCE roles_id_seq RESTART WITH 186;

		</sql>

		<rollback>
		</rollback>
	</changeSet>

</databaseChangeLog>
